laist.com 2018-04-12

# Your Privacy Rights | 89.3 KPCC

You have come to this page from a Web site produced by Southern California Public Radio (SCPR), the operator of KPCC, KVLA, and KUOR. When we refer to KPCC, KVLA, and KUOR in this privacy policy, we are referring to the privacy policy of SCPR. We recognize the importance of privacy to visitors to any SCPR Web site, and we want every user (you) to know how we collect and use information about you when you visit our Web sites. This privacy policy explains what type of information is collected from you when you visit this and other SCPR Web sites, and how we may use that information.

## Contents

  * Information we automatically gather when you visit our site
  * Information you give us
    * Name and contact information
    * Demographic and profile information
    * Credit card information
  * Your California Privacy Rights
  * Contact SCPR
  * Consent
  * Effective Date

## Information We Automatically Gather When You Visit SCPR Web Sites

Like virtually all other Web servers, SCPR's Web server automatically creates log files for each visitor who accesses our site. These "access logs" allow us to make our site more useful to our visitors. The access logs do not record a visitor's name, address, phone number, credit card numbers, or any other personally identifying information. Rather, these log files may contain some or all of the following information:

  * The date of the visit
  * The time and length of the visit
  * The path taken through the Web site
  * The browser being used
  * A list of files downloaded or viewed
  * The amount of time spent listening to audio files
  * The Internet Protocol Address (IP Address) of the machine accessing our Web site*
  * Any errors encountered

*Most Internet Service Providers use a "dynamic" form of assigning IP Addresses. This means that a visitor may have a different IP Address each time he or she visits an SCPR Web site. Also, many Internet Service Providers, including America Online, use "Proxy servers" which provide even more anonymity for visitors.

We use this information to aid the technical administration of the sites and to better understand how each site is functioning for its users. This information may be correlated with your profile, if you have provided this data, to provide special "personalized" services. This information may also be used in aggregate form.

We may track your visit to sections of our Web sites in order for some site features to function properly for you. In some instances, "cookies" or a similar technology may be used to update your registration records with session information. If you do not wish to accept a cookie from SCPR's servers, you can adjust the settings on your browser accordingly. Refusing to accept cookies from the SCPR server may result in some limits on the benefits that we can automatically provide as you enjoy the SCPR Web sites.

SCPR works with a third party, ADTECH, for ad delivery.  The non-personally-identifiable information collected about your visits to this and other web sites may be used in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.  You have the option not to participate (see <http://www.adtech.com/en/service/cookies.html>).

### Nielsen//NetRatings

The use of Nielsen//NetRatings' Web site measurement software assists Southern California Public Radio in analyzing the user experience on our Web sites and improving the structure and ease of use of our Web sites. Nielsen//NetRatings is used to collect such information as the number of unique visitors, how long visitors spend on our Web sites, and common entry and exit points into and from the Web sites. We do not collect personally identifying information from our Web sites unless you choose to provide that information to us.

Our properties may feature Nielsen’s proprietary measurement software which will allow you to contribute to market research, like Nielsen’s TV Ratings. To learn more about the information Nielsen’s software may collect and your choices with regard to it, please [click here](http://www.nielsen.com/digitalprivacy).

Further information about Nielsen//NetRatings including their privacy policy can be found on the Nielsen//NetRatings Web site ([Nielsen Online Privacy Statement](http://www.nielsen-online.com/privacy.jsp?section=leg_scs)).

## Information You Give Us

SCPR does not collect personally-identifying information from SCPR Web sites unless you choose to provide that information to us. Visitors under the age of 18 must obtain permission from their parents or guardians before sending any personally-identifying information to SCPR.

### Name and Contact Information

SCPR may ask visitors (you) to provide certain personal information when you: register for a contest; sign up for an email list; request information; purchase products or services; contribute material that may be used on the Web site (e.g. recipes, program reviews); participate in a forum, bulletin board or chat; or use an SCPR form to become a member of SCPR. SCPR tells you whether a specific piece of information is required at the time it is requested.

This information may be used by SCPR to: verify your identity; manage a contest; gather your editorial comments and feedback; contact you for additional information; and fulfill your order or request. SCPR may also use this information for marketing and promotional purposes. By providing this information, you may receive occasional email from SCPR. SCPR does not share email addresses with third-parties.

When your name and contact information is to be used as part of an SCPR-owned list, you will be informed of that fact, and you will be given the option not to be included on the list. (You may later elect to be removed from an SCPR list by following the instructions provided on the SCPR Web site.)

To maximize the benefits SCPR can provide through its network of public radio Web sites and through qualified associations, your name and postal address may be exchanged for consideration with select companies and organizations, including with other public radio stations and programs. These companies and organizations may attempt to contact you to promote a product or service which they offer. Such contacts from third-parties will only be made with SCPR's consent, and SCPR will only grant its consent when SCPR considers the offer to be of potential interest and benefit to our Web site users.

SCPR will not share, exchange, rent, or sell any of its lists to political parties or candidates for political office.

If you do not want your name and contact information to be used in this way, you may indicate this at the time you provide the information. If an "opt-out" option is not offered, or you decide after you have provided this information that you do not want SCPR to share your information with any company or organization, you may also notify us via our [Contact page](http://www.scpr.org/contact/). SCPR cannot remove your name from any third party's list; you will have to contact them directly.

The Direct Marketing Association (DMA) offers a Mail Preference Service that is designed to assist consumers in decreasing the amount of nonprofit or commercial mail they receive at home. For more information about this service, visit the DMA Web site at: www.the-dma.org and click on the "Consumers" tab.

### Demographic and Profile Information

SCPR occasionally conducts online surveys, sometimes in association with a contest or other offer. These surveys may ask you for demographic information such as ZIP code, age, education or income level. This information is used in an aggregate form to help us understand our audiences and improve our services. Demographic and profile information may be shared with selected third-party organizations, only on an aggregate basis, to describe the nature of our online audiences.

### Credit Card Information

You must be 18 to engage in money-related transactions on an SCPR or APM site. When you do so, you may be asked for a credit card number. All financial transactions take place only on secure servers. Electronic communication of credit card information is sent only in a secured or encrypted format. Your credit card information is considered completely confidential. SCPR and APM strive to be compliant with the Data Security Standard as prescribed by the Payment Card Industry.

## Your California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident, beginning on January 1, 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 may entitle you to receive additional information from us regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes and your right to opt-out of such disclosure. Please direct all such requests to us at the email and/or regular mail address provided below under “Contact SCPR”. If you do not want your name and contact information to be shared with any company or organization, you may notify us at any time by writing to us at the email and/or regular mail addresses designated below.

## Contact SCPR

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or any practices on the SCPR sites, or with to request information pursuant to California Civil Code §1798.83(a), please send us a message via our [contact page](http://www.scpr.org/contact/) or send a letter by regular mail to:

SCPR  
474 South Raymond Avenue  
Pasadena, CA 91105

SCPR reserves the right to change this policy. Any changes to this policy will be posted to this page as soon as reasonably possible, so please check this page periodically.

## Consent

Your use of the SCPR Web site constitutes consent to any policy then in effect.

## Effective date

This policy was last updated on August 26, 2010.
